Inventory of the Papers of Monroe Leigh, 1941 - 2001
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
- International Criminal Court (ICC)
  - American Bar Association (ABA)
    - Press Clippings: Fax from Patricia M. Hanrahan/David Stoelting to Monroe Leigh re: Jesse Helms, 1 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 33)
      Forwarding June 22, 1998 press information from U.N. Court Watch
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, "Semantics Stall Pact Labeling Rape as War Crime" by Alessandra Stanley, New York Times, 9 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 34)
    - Press Clippings: "U.S. Cool to War Crimes Panel" by Charles Trueheart, Washington Post, 10 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 35)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopies of New York Times articles from 15 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 36)
      Photocopy, "U.S. Presses Allies to Rein in Proposed War Crimes Court" by Alessandra Stanley, brief, "Undermining an International Court"
    - Press Clippings: Photocopies of Washington Post briefs, 16 and 17 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 37)
      "Clinton Urges Others to Give Ground on Court" and "War Crimes Conference Remains Divided"
    - Press Clippings: Press Release "Italian Foreign Minister Urges Conference Not to Let Chance to Set Up International Criminal Court Slip from Its Grasp" UN L/ROM/18, 14 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 38)
    - Press Clippings: Articles by IPS-Inter Press Service, TerraViva, July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 39)
      "Torch-Light March", "Treaty? What Treaty",
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, "A Turn in the Road" by Anthony Lewis, New York Times, 20 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 40)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopies of Financial Times Mandate articles from 16, 18, &,amp, 20 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 41)
      "U.N. War Crimes Court Agreed" by James Blitz, July 18, "U.S. Faces Test on War Crimes Court" by James Blitz, July 16, with highlighting - "Diplomats Deliver Judgments on New War Crimes Court" by James Blitz, July 20
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, "A New Court Without the U.S.", Washington Post, 21 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 42)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, "Nations Create War-Crimes Court Despite U.S. Protest" by Neil King, Jr., Wall Street Journal, 20 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 43)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, Letters to the Editor, "U.S. Is Wrong on War Crimes Court", New York Times, 22 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 44)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, "Don't Buy U.S. Excuse on Global Criminal Court" by William Pfaff, International Hearld Tribue, 23 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 45)
    - Press Clippings: "A New Court Without the U.S.", Washington Post, 21 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 46)
    - Press Clippings: From the Washington Post, 26 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 47)
      "America Avoids the Stand" by Thomas Lippman, Op-Ed, "The Trouble with the War Crimes Court" by Fred Hiatt
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, "War Crimes Approval Gives U.S. a Dilemma" by Thomas W. Lippman, Washington Post, 23 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 48)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, briefs from the Economist, 25 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 49)
      "Sorry isn't enough", "A challenge to impunity", "Latin lessons for Asian banks"
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, brief, "A Weak International Court", New York Times, 27 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 50)
    - Press Clippings: Fax from Phil Barringer to Monroe Leigh re: International Criminal Court, 28 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 51)
      Forwarding with comment International Institute for Strategic Studies article "Creating an International Criminal Court" and other assorted articles from July 27 and 28
    - Press Clippings: Clipping and photocopy, "No Frankenstein's Court" by Diane F. Orentlicher, Washington Post, 31 July 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 52)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, letter to the editor, "We Need an International Court" by Kenneth Roth, Wall Street Journal, 18 August 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 53)
    - Press Clippings: Email from Lea Browning blind-copy to Monroe Leigh re: ICC -- Financial Times, 1 September 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 54)
      Forwarding July 31, 1998 letter to the editor by Jeff Laurenti
    - Press Clippings: Letter from Monroe Leigh to Fred Hiatt, Washington Post, regarding July 11, 1999 article, 13 July 1999 (Box-folder 2 - 55)
      With copy of article attached
    - Press Clippings: "An International Criminal Court" letter to the editor by Kenneth Roth, Washington Post, 7 July 1999 (Box-folder 2 - 56)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, "Departing War Crimes Tribunal Chief Assails U.N. Inaction" by Colum Lynch, Washington Post, 9 November 1999 (Box-folder 2 - 57)
    - Press Clippings: "Kosovo Inquiry Confirms U.S. Fears of War Crimes Court" by Seven Lee Myers, New York Times, 3 January 2000 (Box-folder 2 - 58)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, "Yes, A World Court" by Kenneth Roth, Washington Post, 27 June 2000 (Box-folder 2 - 59)
    - Press Clippings: Photocopy, "A World Apart?" by T.R. Goldman, Legal Times, 8 June 1998 (Box-folder 2 - 60)
    - Letters to Washington Post: Fax from Monroe Leigh to Edison Dick re: Letter to Hiatt opposing Helm's bill, 8 September 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 1)
    - Letters to Washington Post: Fax to Fred Hiatt from Monroe Leigh re: inaccuracies in July 11, 1999 Washington Post article, 13 July 1999 (Box-folder 3 - 2)
      post-it attached indicating "Do not send this letter to Ed Dick"
    - Letters to Washington Post: Email from Kristi Gaines to Monroe Leigh re: Lobby Visits on Aug. 29th, 22 August 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 3)
    - Letters to Washington Post: Clipping, "Nato's Good Fight" by Fred Hiatt, Washington Post, 11 July 1999 (Box-folder 3 - 4)
    - Letters to Washington Post: Draft "For the ICC" 16 March 1999 (Box-folder 3 - 5)
      Contains handwritten markup
    - Letters to Washington Post: Letter from Monroe Leigh to Fred Hiatt regarding July 11, 1999 article, 13 July 1999 (Box-folder 3 - 6)
    - Letters to Washington Post: Draft, Letter to editor, re: critics of proposed ICC (not sent) 965 words, 3 August 1999 (Box-folder 3 - 7)
    - Letters to Washington Post: Letter from Fred Hiatt to Monroe Leigh, re: Leigh's letter/thoughts on ICC, 10 January 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 8)
    - Letters to Washington Post: Correspondence between Hiatt and Leigh re: articles on ICC in Washington Post, 5 January 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 9)
    - "Report of the Task Force on an International Criminal Court of the American Bar Association" Benjamin R. Civiletti, Chair, John F. Murphy, Reporter, Alaire Bretz Rieffel, Editor. 1 August 1994 (Box-folder 3 -)
      [Copy available at Law INT38.R4253]
    - Letters to Editors: Submissions for "Toward an International Criminal Court" by Monroe Leigh, June - July 1998 (Box-folder 3 - 10)
      1. to Washington Post, 2. to NYTimes (with penciled edits), 3. to Wall Street Journal
    - War Crimes: Letter from Samuel R. Burger, Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs to Jerome J. Shestack, Chairman, Committee on Conscience, U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum, 16 January 2001 (Box-folder 3 - 11)
    - War Crimes: Letter from Jerome J. Shestack, U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum to President William Clinton, 28 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 12)
    - War Crimes: Press release "Helms on Clinton ICC Signature: 'This Decision Will Not Stand'" with letters attached, 31 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 13)
      Attached letters: November 29, 2000 letter from Lawrence EagleBurger, former Secretary of State, Brent Scowcroft, formder National Security Advisor, Caspar WeinBurger, former Secretary of Defense, Zbigniew Brezezinski, former National Security Advisor, R. James Woolsey, former Director of Central Intelligence, Jeane Kirkpatrick, former Ambassador to the UN, Henry Kissinger, former Secretary of State, Donald Rumsfeld, former Secretary of Defense, Richard V. Allen, former National Security Advisor, George Shultz, former Secretary of State, James A. Baker III, former Secretary of State, and Robert M. Gates, former Director of Central Intelligence, December 22, 2000 letter to Secretary of Defense William S. Cohen and Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff GEneral Henry H. Shelton from Senators Jesse Helms, Chairman of Committee on Foreign Relations and John Warner, Chariman of Committee on Armed Services
    - War Crimes: Letter from 18 U.S. Senators to President William J. Clinton, 21 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 14)
      Signed by Senators Patrick Leahy, Dianne Feinstein, Allen Specter, Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Christopher Dodd, John F. Kerry, Joseph I. Lieberman, James M. Jeffords, Richard J. Durbin, Tom Harkin, Herb Kohl, Charles E. Schumer, Frank R. Lautenberg, Paul Wellstone, Barbara Boxer, Patty Murray, Edward M. Kennedy, Paul S. Sarbanes
    - War Crimes: Letter to President William J. Clinton from several representatives of religious organizations and faith-based groups, 20 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 15)
      Signees include Rev. Michael Dodd, Columban Fathers' Justice &,amp, Peace Office, Rev. Lonnie Turner, Cooperativer (sic) Baptist Fellowship Washington Office, Rabbi David Saperstein, Co-Director of Commission on Social Action of Reform Judaism, Gary Baldridge, Co-Coordinator of Global Missions for the Cooperative Bapatist Fellowship, and Rev. David O. Selzer (Chair), Janey G. Chisholm (Vice Chair), Verna M. Fausey (Secretary), Christopher Pottle (Treasurer), Mary H. MIller (Executive Secretary) of the Episcopal Peace Fellowship
    - War Crimes: Letter to President Clinton from 30 Congressmen, 15 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 16)
      Signees: Patrick J. Kennedy, Sam Farr, Michael Capuano, Pete Stark, Dennis Kucinich, James McGovern, Sherrod Brown, Albert Wynn, Bill Parscrell, Jr., Jan Schakowsky, Barbara Lee, Barney Frank, Maurice Hinchey, Maxine Waters, Carolyn Maloney, Jesse Jackson, Jr., William Delahunt, Shelia Jackson Lee, Tim Holden, Nancy Pelosi, Eddie Bernice Johnson, Chaka Fattah, Edolphus Towns, Tammy Baldwin, Lucille Royball-Allard, Donald Payne, Major Owens, John Lewis, Jerrold Nalder, John Tierney, Bobby Rush, Lynn Woolsey
    - War Crimes: Letter to President Clinton from Washington Working Group on the ICC, 20 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 17)
    - War Crimes: Letter to President Clinton from Committee of Former Nuremberg Prosecutors for A Permanent International Criminal Court, In re: Rome Treaty for International Criminal Court, 6 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 18)
    - War Crimes: Letter to President Clinton from Recipients of the Eleanor Roosevelt Award, 20 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 19)
    - War Crimes: Letter from the National Council of Women's Organizations, November 30, 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 20)
    - War Crimes: Letter to President Clinton from senior retired military officers, 22 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 21)
      Signees: Rear Admiral Eugene J. Carroll, Jr., Lieutenant General Robert G. Gard, Jr., Lieutenant Robert O. Muller, Chaplain (Major General) Kermit D. Johnson, Colonel Daniel Smith, Major General John B. Kidd, and Vice Admiral John J. Shanahan
    - War Crimes: Statement of Senator Leahy before the Senate re: the International Criminal Court, 15 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 22)
    - War Crimes: Agenda for Washington Working Group on the ICC, 16 January 2001 (Box-folder 3 - 23)
      With handwritten notes
    - War Crimes: Copy of Subtitle C, Sec. 821 of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2000 and 2001 2000 - 2001 (Box-folder 3 - 24)
    - War Crimes: Materials pertaining to the right to a trial by Jury in the US Military Courts, 2000 [1982, 1992, 1998] (Box-folder 3 - 25)
      (contains flags and handwritten notes), 1. Memo from Lee Caplan re: The Right to Trial by Jury in US Military Courts - Martial, August 11, 2000, 2. 727 Military Triers of Fact: Needless Deprivation of Constitutional Protections? By Gary Michael Heil in Hastings College of the Law 1982, 3. 103 The Court-Martial Panel Selection Process: A Critical Analysis by Major Stephen A. Lamb in Military Law Review, Summer 1992, 4. 1 He Called ofr his Pipe, and he called for his bowl, and he called for his members three - selection of military juries by the sovereign: Impediment to Military Justice by Major Guy P. Glazier in Military Law Revew, October 1998, 5. Citations list, Database JLR
    - War Crimes: Correspondence and drafts edits for report to ABA's Section of International Law and Practice re: ICC, September - October 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 26)
      Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Brian Newquist, Lea Browning, Barbara L. Stone, Cynthia Price, David Stoelting, John Washburn, Martha W. Barnett, Bruce Swartz, contains numerous handwritten notes, markup, edits, and personal correspondence regarding drafts
    - War Crimes Working Group: Official Correspondence re: ICC and Rome Treaty, October 1999 - December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 27)
      1. ML to ICTY Office of Public Information Services, The Hague, re: Request for Copy of ICTY Judges' Submission to the Fourth Session of the U.N. Preparatory Commission for the International Criminal Court Regarding Rules of Evidence and Procedue, April 12, 2000, 2. ML to Lloyd N. Cutler re: Barbara Crossette's NYTimes article on Pres. signing treaty before end of year, December 11, 2000, 3. Samuel Burger to David Stoelting re: US policy towards ICC and the Rome Treaty, November 9, 2000, 4. ML to Samuel Burger re: ABA adn ICC and US acceptance of Rome Treaty, October 13, 1999
    - War Crimes Working Group: Draft Statement and ABA Recommendation re: US agreeing to Rome Treaty of ICC, 29 November &,amp, 8 December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 28)
      1. Daniel Magraw to [cc. ML], 2. ML to Edison Dick
    - War Crimes Working Group: Correspondence re: appointments for working group on ICC, Nov. 17, 1999 &,amp, July 19, 1999 (Box-folder 3 - 29)
      1. Rona Mears to Thoams Allen, 2. Rona Mears to ML
    - War Crimes Working Group: Handwritten comments re: WICC agenda, resolutions, op-eds, 14 December 1999 (Box-folder 3 - 30)
      Handwritten in blue ink
    - War Crimes Working Group: Clippings, photocopies, articles re: the ICC, February 1999 - December 2000 (Box-folder 3 - 31)
      Handwritten comments on some, highlights,
    - War Crimes Working Group: "Working Group on International Criminal Court Procedures", 26 April 1999 (Box-folder 3 - 32)
      Not all of the documents appear to be extra copies
    - War Crimes Working Group: Correspondence re: ICC with Australian Representatives, June - July 1999 (Box-folder 3 - 33)
      Contains markup, post-it notes, and notations
    - War Crimes Working Group: Document Drafts, June 1999 (Box-folder 4 - 1)
      Contains notations, 1. Part 6 of the Rome Statute, 2. ABA Recommendation re: ICC, 3. Australian Rule 92, 4. Proposed Rules of Procedure and Evidence for the ICC, 5. Rules of Procedure and Evidence of the ICC (Australian Draft)
    - War Crimes Working Group: Correspondence re: Proposed Rules of Procedure and Evidence, 2 &,amp, 9 June 1999 (Box-folder 4 - 2)
      1. Re: ICC: Rules of Procedure and Evidence, 2. Re: Proposed Rules for Siracusa Meeting
    - War Crimes Working Group: Proposed Paragraphs for Section of Criminal Justice and International Law and Practice (Box-folder 4 - 3)
      Copies cc'd with notes sent to: Michael Johnson &,amp, Neal Sonnett, David Stoelting, James Silkenat, Gerold Libby, William Hannay
    - War Crimes Working Group: Drafts: Part 7. Rules of Evidence (multiple versions), 28 May 1999 - 11 June 1999 (Box-folder 4 - 4)
      Contains handwritten notations and markup
    - War Crimes Working Group: Draft Documents, Apr - Oct 1999 (Box-folder 4 - 5)
      Contains markup, notations, post-its, 1. ABA Section of Interantional Law and Practice Report to the House of Delegates Recommenation, 2. Proposed ABA Resolution concerning participation by the United Staets, 3. Report to Section, Re: draft report on the PrepCom, 4. Minutes of the Meeting of the Council of the ABA Section of International Law and Practice, 5. Revised Rules on Part 6, 6. Proposed rules for Special proceedings to Protect a Victim, Witness, or Accused, 7. Draft Basic Principles and Guidelines on the Right to a Remedy and Reparations for Victims of Violations of International Human Rights and Humanitarian Law, 8. ICC Rules of Procedure and Evidence comments, 9. July 12 draft rules on in camera evidence and electronic testimony, 10. In Camera Proceedings and Testimony by Electronic Means: Proposed Revised Rules, 11. Revised rules to replace ABA Rule 72 as well as Australian Rules 88 &,amp, 89 and French Rule 38.1, 12. Subsection 2. Rules of Evidence, 13. International Seminar on victim's access to the ICC, 14. Discussion Paper on Rules for PArt 6, 15. Draft Resolution for Consideration by the Section of International Law adn Practice at the Toronto Meeting
    - War Crimes Working Group: Correspondence, April, July, November 1999 (Box-folder 4 - 6)
      Contains post-it notes, highlights, notations, Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, WICC group, Robert Stein, M. Cherif Bassiouni, Bruce Swartz, Barbara M.G. Lynn, William Hannay, Lea Browning, Jerome Shestack, Greg Stanton, David Stoelting, Edison Dick
    - War Crimes Working Group: Notes / Articles, July 1999 (Box-folder 4 - 7)
      Contains handwritten notes, markup, notations
    - War Crimes Working Group: Documents, Sept &,amp, Dec 1999 (Box-folder 4 - 8)
      1. Rules relating to defense counsel, victims and witnesses, 2. Remarks made by Judge Gabrielle Kirk McDonald, Pres. Of the International Criminal Tirbunal for the former Yugoslavia, to the Perparatory Commission for the ICC
    - War Crimes Working Group: Correspondence, Sep - Nov 1999 (Box-folder 4 - 9)
      Contains handwritten notes, Correspondencts include: Thomas Allen, Rhona Mears, Monroe Leigh, James Silkenat, Karin Calvo-Goller, Greg Stanton, Roland Homet, Bruce Swartz,
    - War Crimes Working Group: Drafts, 2000 (Box-folder 4 - 10)
      Contains markup, handwritten notes and post-it notes, Safeguards for US Personnel under the Rome Treaty for the ICC, ABA Recommendation on ICC (multiple versions), Draft Statement (Dec. 8, 2000), Report on the Proposed ICC (multiple versions)
    - War Crimes Working Group: Documents, 1998 - 2001 (Box-folder 4 - 11)
      Contains markup and notes, ASPA draft bill text, APA Model Code of Judicial Conduct, Policy fo the Nixon Administration as Revealed in Public Statements, Expropriation in International Law, Ratification of the Rome Statue of the International Criminal Court by Germany Statement, ABA Recommendation on ICC, Fall 2000 Retreat ICC Report with Recommendation, Ambassador Scheffer's Statement at the Human Rights Caucus, State of Monroe Leigh re: HR 4654, Panel on Foreign Policy Gridlock at Annual Meeting of Association, WICC group contacts, Remarks at House of Delegates Meeting Nashville,
    - War Crimes Working Group: Articles / Press, June 1994 - 2001 (Box-folder 4 - 12)
      From: DefenseNews.com, Cato Institute, Diplomat, Foreign Affairs, Military Law Review, American Society of International Law, Federal News Service, American Journal of International Law, Wall Street Journal, Washington Times, Reuters, New Yrok times, Congressional Testimony, The International Lawyer
    - War Crimes Working Group: Correspondence, January 1998 - July 2001 (Box-folder 5 - 1)
      Correspondents include: Monroe Leigh, Cynthia Price, WICC email list, Benmamin Ferencz, Carl Christol, Heather Hamilton, Stephen Rickard, Michael Capuano, Henry Hyde, Burns Weston, David Stoelting, Jerome Shestack, Jackson Diehl, Keithe Nelson, Enid Adler, John Washburn, Daniel Magraw, Willaim Hannay, David Scheffer
    - War Crimes Working Group: Legal Cases, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 5 - 2)
      Contains handwritten notes and post-it notes. 1. 893 F. Supp.65, 1995 US Dist., Civil Action No. 95-1097 (RCL), August 31, 1995, 2. 1996 US App., Docket No. 95-2462, Decided August 29, 1996
    - War Crimes Working Group: Notes, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 5 - 3)
      Handwritten notes in pencil and ink
    - War Crimes Working Group: ABA Criminal Justice Section Council Meeting Agenda Book, 18 - 19 November 2000 (Box-folder 5 - 4)
      Contains post-it notes
    - War Crimes Working Group: Memo from Brian Newquiest to Monroe Leigh "Original Signatories" to the Rome Treaty, 29 September 2000 (Box-folder 5 - 5)
      Contains highlights and post-it notes
    - War Crimes Working Group: Correspondence re: Rome Treaty, June 2000 (Box-folder 5 - 6)
      Contains handwritten post-it notes and notations
    - War Crimes Working Group: Relevant Articles of Rome Treaty, n.d. (Box-folder 5 - 7)
    - War Crimes Working Group Defence Unit: Travel plans and Conference agendas, September - December, 1999 (Box-folder 5 - 8)
      1. Reservation Confirmation, 2. Provisional Work Plan, 3. Predicted Ratified Dates, 4. Programme: Independent Defence before the ICC, 5.1999 Human Rights Day Community Awards Luncheon, 6. ABA Reps on Preparatory Comm.
    - War Crimes Working Group Defence Unit: Draft Proposals, 1999 (Box-folder 5 - 9)
      Contains some markup, 1. PCNICC/1999/DP.8/Add.2/Rev.1, 2. PCNICC/1999/WGRPE(4)/DP.2, 3. PCNICC/1999/L.4, 4. PCNICC/1999/L.4, 5. PCNICC/1999/WGRPE/RT.5/Rev.1, 6. PCNICC/1999/WGRPE/RT.5/Rev.1/Add.1/Corr.1, 7. PCNICC/1999/WGRPE/RT.5/Rev.1/Add.2, 8. PCNICC/1999/WGRPE/RT.7, 9. PCNICC/1999/WGRPE(4)/Rt.1, 10. PCNICC/1999/WGRPE(4)/DP.3/Rev.1, 11. PCNICC/1999/WGEC/INF/3, 12. PCNICC/1999/WGEC/DP.27
    - War Crimes Working Group Defence Unit: Statements &,amp, Documents, 1999 (Box-folder 5 - 10)
      Contains markup, 1. PCNICC/1999/L.4/Add.1, 2. US Statement before the UN General Assembly Sixth Committee, The Rome Treaty on the ICC, October 21, 1999, 3. (same as 2 w/different markup), 4. Senate Foreign Relations Comm Hearing, October 20, 1999, 5. PCNICC/1999/L.4, 6. Activity Report 1997-1999 Conference on Independent Defence before the ICC, 1-2 November 1999, The Hague, Netherlands, 7. A Strong Defense Before the International Criminal Court, Presentation for the ABA, August 10, 1999, by Elise Groulx
    - War Crimes Working Group FSIA: Articles on FSIA in historical perspective, n.d. (Box-folder 5 - 11)
      1. Excerpt from "The Price of Terror: One bomb. One Plane. 270 Lives. The History-Making Struggle for Justice After Pan Am 103" by Allan Gerson and Jerry Adler (HarperCollins Publishers), 2. "The Constitution and Jrisdiction over Foreign States: The 1996 Amendments to the Foreign Sovereign Immunities Act in Perspective" by Lee M. Caplan (contains flagged pages)
    - War Crimes Working Group FSIA: Congressional Materials, 1994 - 1995 (Box-folder 5 - 12)
      1. Testimoney of Jamison s. Borek before the subcommittee on Courts and Adminsitrative Practice of the Committee on the Judiciary United States Senate on S. 825, June 21, 1994 (contains post-it message from Mark Said and comments within text), 2. Fax re: Draft letter to Sen. Biden supporting FSIA aka S. 735, June 2, 1995
    - War Crimes Working Group FSIA: Memoranda re: Amendments, 1995, 2000 (Box-folder 6 - 1)
      1. Mark S. Said correspondence, June 1, 1995 (contains business card), 2. Re: ILA, European Convention on State Immunity and FSIA., November 13, 2000, 3. Re: Proposed Amendments to FSIA, October 17, 2000 (contains markup)
    - War Crimes Working Group FSIA: Reports from the Working Group, 2000 (Box-folder 6 - 2)
      1. Section Reports with Receommendations, Council Summary (contains inserts), 2. Draft Recommendation and Report on the US Foreign Sovereign Immunities Act, 2000 (contains Monroe Leigh signature)
    - War Crimes Working Group FSIA: Historical Cases and Precedence, [1789] 1984 (Box-folder 6 - 3)
      Many photocopies, Contains post-it notes, handwritten notes, underlines
    - War Crimes San Diego Meeting: Correspondence, January - March, 2001 (Box-folder 6 - 4)